本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 水仙花开 Ellie 中二豆奶 符号看象限 落叶夏天
校对： 海之南  后期： 海之南
《心灵缉凶》前情提要
Previously on Cracked..
- 你是... - 抱歉
- And you are...? - Sorry.
瑞秋・芬顿 集团犯罪联合特遣部队
Rachel Fenton, Organized Crime Joint Taskforce.
雷德利医生在您面前
What kinds of things
是怎样评价布莱克警官的
would Dr. Ridley tell you about Detective Black?
她会定期向我汇报艾登的心理状态
She would keep me apprised of Aidan's state of mind.
- 艾登 - 艾登 等等
- Aidan... - Aidan, wait!
加利格拉很担心你
Caligra was worried about you.
所以让我帮忙留意一下
She asked me to keep an eye on you.
我起初这么做是为了我们小组
I did it for the unit in the beginning,
后来是为了你
and then I did it for you.
我不能忍受了
I can't do this anymore.
我正要找您呢 我要换搭档
Just the person I'm looking for. I want a divorce.
在另行通知之前 艾登 你和里奥一组
Until further notice, Aidan, you're partnered with Leo.
- 波比 你和丹妮拉一组 - 什么
- Poppy, you're with Daniella. - What?!
- 那你想要什么 - 孩子
- So what do you want? - A child.
你的儿子
Your son.
我当初不该放弃他
I never should've given him up.
有伏击 走 趴下 趴下
It's an ambush! Go! Get down! Get down!
趴下 趴下
Get down! Get down!
趴下 趴下 别进去 不要
Get down! Get down! Don't go back inside, no!
不 别进去
No! Don't go inside
# 我今早起床 #
I got out of bed today
# 对上帝发誓 我看不见我的脸 #
Swear to God, couldn't see my face
# 我今早起床 #
I got out of bed today
# 注视着一缕灵魂 #
Staring at a ghost
# 你看到我的灵魂了吗 #
Oh have you seen my ghost
# 看到了吗 看到了吗 #
Seen my ghost, seen my ghost
# 哦 你看到我的灵魂了吗 #
Oh have you seen my ghost
# 它凝视着地面 #
Staring at the ground
心灵缉凶 第一季第12集
抱歉
Sorry.
- 嘿 - 嘿 是你啊
- Hey. - Hey there.
- 我没打给你 - 你本该打来的
- I didn't call. - You should have.
我这段时间一直在忙工作的事
I've been busy at work.
我非常肯定我们在同一栋楼上班
I'm pretty sure we workin the same building.
- 我一直想打给你来着 - 别这样 热情一点嘛
- I've been meaning to. - Please just don't try and be sweet.
- 不知道怎么做 - 学学就会了
- Wouldn't know how. - Maybe you could learn.
每当我跟你说话
That thing you do where I say something
你针锋相对地反驳我的样子 我挺喜欢
and you turn it around and you stick it to me? I like that.
很好
Good.
那我们约个时间坐一坐 你什么时候有空
So let's set this up. When are you free?
哦 见鬼 忘记给手机充电了
Aw, shit. I forgot to plug my phone in.
昨晚整夜没睡 搬家具
Was up all night. Moving furniture.
当然 不然你还可能干嘛 还是睡不着吗
Of course. What else could you be doing? Still not sleeping?
见鬼 一小时前有人打电话找我
Damn it. I went on call an hour ago.
- 可你没在 - 我要走了
- Only it turns out you weren't. - I gotta go.
哦...
Yeah...
慢着
Not so fast.
我的电话
My number.
别让汗水给洗掉了
Don't sweat that off.
祝你愉快
Have a good one.
- 睡过头了 - 我也想啊
- Sleep in? - I wish.
手机没电了 什么情况
My phone died. What's up?
四个家伙闯进这家珠宝店行窃 前后不到十分钟
Four guys blew in and out of this jewelry store in like less than a minute.
太牛了
Impressive.
看上去不值得啊 他们盗的货价值多少
Hardly looks worth it. How much did they get?
还不清楚 珠宝店老板正在路上
Don't know yet. Jewelry store owner's on his way down.
貌似是保险柜里的东西被盗了
It looks like whatever was in the safe.
那把我们召集过来做什么
So why were we called in?
协助盗窃侦破组
Special request from Robbery Squad.
似乎是有个罪犯发疯了
Apparently one of the guys goes nuts,
袭击了一位女性路人
he attacks a female bystander,
然后开始朝天开枪
starts shooting in the air.
他的同伙只好把他拖走
His partners had to haul him off of her.
受害者在哪儿
Where is she now?
圣・斯蒂芬医院 丹妮拉和波比去找她谈话了
St. Stephens. Daniella and Poppy they're headed down there to talk to her.
我们掌握了哪些线索
What have we got?
使用了非常先进的爆炸装置
Some pretty elite explosive use.
锥形装药 破坏极小
Shaped charges, minimum damage.
连展示柜都没震碎
They didn't even break the display cases.
- 厉害 - 很厉害
- Pros. - Good ones.
实在太厉害了
I mean really good.
我当时很害怕 以为他要开枪杀我
I was terrified. I thought he was going to shoot me.
你可以给我们描述下当时的场景吗
Can you take us through what happened?
他们出来时我正在家门口
I was at my door when they all came out.
他们带着面具 应该有辆货车 然后他看见我了
They had masks. There was a van, I think. And then he saw me.
一个盗贼
One of the robbers?
他正四周环视 然后就看到了我 他就...
He was looking all around and then he saw me. And he just...
我想开门进去 但他把我撞倒了
I tried to get inside, but he knocked me down.
他压住我 朝天开枪
He got on top of me. He was shooting,
然后他的同伙把他拉走了
and then the other men pulled him off.
他们知道他疯掉了
He was crazy, they knew it.
他们把他往车里塞的时候 他一个劲儿的挣扎
They put him in the van, he was struggling.
你可以给我们描述一下吗 是高是矮 是黑是白
Can you describe him for me? Was he tall? Short? Skin color?
我只看到面具 但他移动起来很滑稽 动作很僵硬
All I saw was the mask. But he moved funny. Stiff.
往一边倾斜
Leaning to one side.
你知道是什么让他发疯的吗
Do you know what set him off?
可能是警报声
The siren maybe?
远处有救护车的警报声
There was a siren in the distance, an ambulance.
他一听到就朝我奔过来
As soon as he heard it, he was coming for me.
往一边倾斜 动作怪异 看不出身高 肤色
Leaning to one side, acting crazy, no height, no skin color.
- 哇 她可帮大忙了 - 当你惊慌失措时
- Wow, she was a big help. - When you're that scared,
所有的细节都会混在一起
the details can get all jumbled up.
惊慌失措 就像那个害怕警报声的盗贼
Scared, like the robber who's afraid of a siren?
这么说 我们的线索有 高度紧张的情景设置
So, we have a high-stress situation
让人失控发疯的噪音声响
and noise triggering an erratic outburst,
也就是警笛
the siren.
- 我可以列上一整天 - 哦 千万别
- I could list things all day long. - Oh, please don't.
- 看看他们都干了些什么 - 你是店老板吗
- Look what they've done to me. - Are you the owner?
- 让一下 我要看看后面 - 不行 不行
- Excuse me, I have to see in the back. - No, no.
- 嘿 老兄 放松 放松 - 他们打开了保险柜吗
- Hey, buddy, easy, easy. - Did they get in the safe?
- 只动了保险柜 - 哦 天呐 我完蛋了
- Only thing they touched. - Oh, my God. No! I'm screwed.
等等 为什么这么说
Hold on. Why do you say that?
这些石头 还没上保险呢
The stones. They weren't insured yet.
- 什么石头 - 我这是个小店啊
- What stones? - I'm a small store.
通常 我只保留价值四五万的现货
Normally I keep maybe 40, 50,000 in stock.
但我是参团合伙批发的 因为这样比较实惠
But I buy wholesale as part of a group. We get better leverage.
我们每个月换一个人保管这些石头
Every month it's someone's turn to hold the stones
- 直到我们分货 - 价值多少
- 'til we make the divvy. - And how much are we talking about?
- 零售额大概1.5 - 百万
- Maybe 1.5 retail. - Million?
- 现在你们明白我为什么要疯了吧 - 抱歉
- Now you see why I'm freaking out? - Excuse me.
不能进 老兄 不能进
Stay here, man, just stay here.
- 这些石头在这里有多久了 - 两天
- How long had the stones been here for? - Two days.
明天我们就要分货了 有的时候需要...
Tomorrow we make the division. Sometimes it gets to be a bit of a...
事先商定 你懂吗
discussion, you understand?
这绝不是意外
This is no accident.
好的 我们需要店里员工的名单
OK. We're gonna need a list of all your employees,
以及所有合伙珠宝店的店名及地址
and the name and addresses of all these stores in your group
以及其他经常跟你做交易的人 明白了吗
and anyone else you deal with on a regular basis, alright?
- 有监控录像吗 - 有
- Any surveillance video? - Yeah,
这里一个 还有那里
one there, and there.
这些家伙不是第一次出手 他们肯定有犯罪记录
These guys are not first timers.They have to have records.
盗窃侦破组说全加拿大都没有匹配记录
Robbery Squad says there's no match for it in Canada.
- 哪一方面的 - 主要是爆炸装置
- No match for what part? - The explosives mainly.
不常见 整个经过都不常见 武器
Not common. But the whole thing's not common. The weapons.
速度 以及他们连看都不看一眼展示柜的态度
The speed. The way these guys don't even look at the display cases.
等下 倒退
Hold on. Back that up.
好 停 开始播放 就这里
OK, stop. Play. That, right there.
这些手势 我之前见过
Those hand signals. I've seen that before.
在苏丹与无国界医生组织一起的时候
With Doctors Without Borders in the Sudan.
你觉得这些家伙是非洲人
You think these guys are African?
不 我觉得他们是军人
No. I think they're military.
我见过特种部队的人用这一模一样的手势
I've seen Special Ops guys use those same hand signals
整个任务执行过程中一句话不说
and run a complete mission in total silence.
- 怎么 - 我在想
- What? - I'm thinking
如果他们是军人 也许警报声引发了他们的压力反应
if these guys are military, maybe the siren triggered some kind of stress response.
创伤后应激障碍 你是这么觉得的
PTSD? That's your theory?
是的 虽然无法解释一切
Well, it doesn't explain everything,
但肯定是有可能的
but it's definitely possible.
从军人的角度来看是符合的
The military angle fits.
不然你还能怎么解释这些家伙如此擅长爆炸装置
How else would you explain these guys getting so good at using explosives
又没留过案底
without leaving a criminal record?
员工里有退役军人吗
Any of the employees exmilitary?
没有 但公司确实
No. But the company does use
雇佣装甲汽车公司运货 等等
an armored car company for deliveries. Hold on.
没错 这个 杰西・鲍威尔
Yeah, here it is. Jesse Powell.
第123团退役的下士
Ex-corporal in the 123rd Regiment.
汽车公司一个多月前解雇了他
The car company fired him just over a month ago.
也许他对此很愤怒
Maybe he's angry about it.
也许他看中机会赚钱 或者招募其他退伍兵
Or maybe he just saw an opportunity to cash in or recruit some other veterans.
我们去看看他
Let's go take a look at him.
什么事
Yes?
我是艾登・布莱克警探 这是里奥・贝克特
I'm Detective Aidan Black, this is Leo Beckett.
- 我们找杰西・鲍威尔 - 他干什么了
- We're looking for Jesse Powell. - What did he do?
我们只是想跟他谈谈 他在家吗
We just want to talk to him. Is he home?
- 他不住这里 - 他的救济金寄到这里的是吧
- Jesse doesn't live here. - His disability checks come here, right?
事情很复杂
It's complicated.
- 你能说详细点吗 - 好 进来吧
- Maybe you could explain it to us. - Alright, come in.
从阿富汗退伍回来之后
Jesse stayed with us for a few months
杰西和我们一起住了几个月
after he got out of the service in Afghanistan.
从他的表现来看 感觉他仍然在战场
You'd think he was still there, from the way he behaved.
一半的时间 他都不睡床 睡地板
Half the time he'd sleep on the floor instead of his own bed.
- 他什么时候搬走的 - 大约六个月前
- When did he move out? - About six months ago.
我们让他走的
We asked him to leave.
他现在在哪里
So where is he now?
我们不知道
We don't...
- 我们和他断了联系 - 这不是我们的错
- we've sort of lost touch with him. - It wasn't our fault.
我们制定计划的时候 他也不来 即使来了也是醉醺醺的
When we made plans, he wouldn't show up. If he did, he was drunk.
卢卡斯 我说过不要偷看
Lucas! I told you not to spy.
那是杰西的儿子
That's Jesse's son.
杰西最近有工作吗
Has Jesse been working much lately?
上次问他的时候 他在开装甲汽车
He was driving an armored car last time we talked.
现在不干了
Not anymore.
他偶尔过来拿救济金 我也不清楚
Well, he stops in once in a while to pick up a check. I don't know.
鲍威尔先生 我们急需找到他
Look, Mr. Powell, we really need to find him.
你肯定有办法联系到他的
There's gotta be some way you can contact him.
我希望有 但是杰西
I wish I could. But Jesse's...
我们是兄弟
We're brothers, you know.
有的时候 好像我总会惹火他
Sometimes, it just seems like...I push his buttons.
他想见你们
Hey, he wanted to meet you.
你们在谈论爸爸吗 他会来给我过生日吗
Are you talking about Dad? Is he coming to my birthday?
- 就在两天后 - 他当然会来 卢卡斯
- It's in two days. - Of course he is, Lucas.
- 他无论如何不会错过的 - 我觉得不对
- He wouldn't miss it for the world. - I don't buy it.
那是他弟弟 他在保护弟弟
He's the guy's brother. He's protecting him.
不
No.
杰西的行为明显给他的婚姻造成了问题
Jesse's behaviour is clearly causing problems in that marriage.
但你真觉得杰西会抛弃孩子 离开这里吗
Still, you think Jesse's really gonna leave town with his kid here?
再说 如果他患有创伤后应激障碍
Plus, if he's suffering from post-traumatic stress...
又来这套 你从哪儿得来的结论
Again with the PTSD? Where do you get that?
你知道在回国老兵中
You know that occupational stress injuries
应激障碍很普遍
are common among vets returning,
尤其是从阿富汗回来的老兵
especially from Afghanistan.
再加上酗酒和睡地板
Add that to the drunkenness and sleeping on the floor...
很快 结论是他是个喜欢开枪抢银行的精神病患者
Presto! We have our trigger-happy, bank-robbing psychopath.
我说的不是这个
That's not what I'm saying.
罪案心理分析科
Psych Crimes.
找你的
It's for you.
艾登・布莱克
Aidan Black.
我是乔治・鲍威尔 关于我弟弟杰西 我有个想法
Hey, it's George Powell. I had a thought about my brother Jesse.
- 你知道他在哪里吗 - 你答应我
- You know where he is? - You promise me
不要伤害他 好吗 他需要帮助
that you're not gonna hurt him. OK? He needs help.
鲍威尔先生 告诉我他在哪里
Tell me where he is, Mr. Powell.
有时我带卢卡斯去市区
I take Lucas downtown sometimes,
的一个收容所
to a homeless shelter.
无论我妻子怎么说 孩子都需要见父亲
The boy needs to see his father, no matter what my wife says.
- 你有地址吗 - 有的
- You have an address? - Yeah, yeah.
救助站的人说他在这里
The guy at the shelter said that he's down here.
好
Alright.
退后点
You know what, just stay back,
- 以防万一 - 好
- just... just in case. - OK.
杰西
Jesse?
我们是警察
Police.
给 再来杯咖啡
Here you go, another coffee.
你在装甲汽车联盟里工作了多久
So you were with Alliance Armored Cars for how long?
- 不知道 六个月吧 - 你为什么被解雇
- I don't know. Six months. - Why'd you get fired?
工作时喝酒
Drinking on the job.
你有没有给铁杉珍稀宝石运过货
You ever deliver to Hemlock Rare Gems?
偶尔
Once in a while.
你知道那家店今天早上被抢劫了吗
You know they got robbed this morning?
几个人炸开了保险箱
Team of guys blew open the safe.
原来 保险箱里有
Turns out there was an unusually
异常多的宝石
large stock of gems on hand.
好吧
Yeah, well...
对了 是用你之前开的车运过去的
Delivered by your old truck, by the way.
和我无关
Nothing to do with me.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
当然 我怎么会知道有特快专递
Yeah, how would I know about some special delivery?
店主说运送日期是固定的
Well, the owner told me it happens on a regular basis,
和你还在职的时候一样
even back when you were working there.
杰西 昨晚你在哪里
Where were you last night, Jesse?
不记得了
I don't know.
我昨天不清醒 喝太多了
I was barely functional yesterday. Drank too much.
- 店几点被劫的 - 很早 早上六点
- When was the store robbed? - Early. Six A.M.
我在救济站的床上 你可以和那边确认
Well, I was in my bunk. You can check with the shelter.
他们肯定记得
They'll remember.
我在那儿还吐了
I left a little... mess.
所以他们把我赶出来了
It's why they kicked me out.
一定很
Must've been...
你被解雇肯定生气
kind of pissed off when you got fired.
不
No.
或许你跟以前军队的朋友说起过
Maybe you told some of the old military buddies about it?
没有
No.
是个好故事 大量宝石运到小店里
It's a good story. Big shipment to a little store.
不不不
No. No. No. No!
也许你不记得了 也许你醉了
Maybe you don't remember. Maybe you were drunk.
如果我醒着 我肯定记得 好吗
If I'm awake, then I fricking remember, okay?
- 是吗 今天几号  - 我 谁关心今天几号
- Really. What's the date today? - I... Who cares?
比如你儿子卢卡斯 他可能会关心
Your son, Lucas, for one. He might care.
他要过生日了
He's got a birthday coming up.
今天几号了
What day is it?
十二号
It's the 12th.
好吧
Okay.
跟我讲讲你军队里的老战友
Tell me about your old army buddies.
- 我不想说 - 你们关系好吗
- I'm not talking about them. - Were you guys close?
- 我不想说 - 好吧 听我说
- I'm not talking about them. - Alright, well listen to me.
如果他们其中有人精神失控 光天化日在街上开枪呢
How about if one of them lost his shit and shot up a street in broad daylight?
你能帮我们
You can help us here.
大伙儿 救助站证实他整晚都在
So, guys, the shelter confirmed that he was there all night.
他们夜间锁门 早上七点才开门
They lock the place up, nobody gets out before 7.
- 所以他不在现场 - 真是太巧合了
- So he wasn't there. - It's a pretty strong coincidence.
我觉得他知道一些事情 没告诉我们
I think he knows something he's not telling us.
找出他的服役记录 看谁是他战友
Pull his service records, let's find out who he served with.
放他走吗
Do we let him go?
不 请不要让我等
No, please... please don't put me on hold.
我等会儿打给你 谢谢
I have to call you back. Thanks.
鲍威尔先生 我是雷德利医生
Mr. Powell? I'm Dr. Ridley,
心理医生
psychiatrist.
心理医生也能当警察了
They let shrinks be cops?
现在我们能做很多事
You'd be surprised at what they let us do nowadays.
你接受心理辅导了吗
are you getting any counselling?
跟你有什么关系
I don't see how that's any of your business.
恕我直言
Don't mean to be rude.
我非常理解
No, I completely understand,
但我可以为你在圣・斯蒂芬's医院安排评估
but I can arrange an assessment for you at St. Stephen's.
- 那儿有很多治疗方法 - 治疗什么
- There are a lot of treatment options. - Treatment for what?
不是心理医生也看得出你状态不好
Look, it doesn't take a shrink to see that you're not doing so well.
你之前在阿富汗服役
You were in Afghanistan?
许多征战归来的人状态都不是很好
A lot of people coming home are not doing great.
嗯
Yeah.
听着 你不必独自面对这种状况
Look, you don't have to go through this alone.
- 我们有支援团 和药物治疗 - 简直是扯淡
- There's support groups, medication. - It's all crap.
好吧 请把这个拿着
OK, please take this.
请你好好考虑一下
Please. And just think about it.
从退役老兵事务部得到了些帮助
Got some cooperation from Veteran's Affairs.
从杰西・鲍威尔所在的部队找到了些资料
Current files from Jesse Powell's unit,
至少有那些退役老兵的
at least those no longer serving.
- 你可以带回家看 - 谁说我要回家
- You can take them home. - Who says I'm going home?
别干了 艾登
Pack it in, Aidan.
好的
I will.
- 你得休息会儿 - 毫无疑问是的
- You should get some sleep. - No doubt.
我再待五分钟 你先走吧
I'm 5 minutes behind you, man. Just go.
我说要你回家
I said go home.
我犯什么错了 工作到很晚吗
What's the crime? Working late?
等下 我有点儿头绪了
Wait. I got something.
看
Watch.
你看他怎么拿包 用他的前臂托着
You see how he picks up the bag, he scoops it with his forearm?
他的手不管用 是假肢
His hand doesn't work. It's a prosthetic.
- 你确定 - 不信你送去分析科
- Are you sure? - Send it to analysis.
- 他们会说我是对的 - 什么是对的
- They'll say I'm right. - Right about what?
其中一个劫匪用假肢
One of the robbers has a prosthetic hand.
杰西的部队里有没有这样一个人
Anyone in Jesse's unit missing one?
左手还是右手
Right or left?
- 你知道是谁吗 - 没有 就是问问
- You got someone? - No. Just asking.
- 里奥 你那堆资料里有没有 - 没有 只有一个没腿的
- Leo, anyone in your pile? - No, just got a guy with no legs.
联系退伍军人事务部 看看他们能不能帮忙
Get over to Veterans Affairs. See if they can help out.
- 这就去 - 这么说你现在相信我了
- On it. - So you believe me now?
是的 我相信你
Yeah, I believe you.
但并不意味着你就可以
But that doesn't mean you get to treat this place
把这里当成街边的汽车旅馆
like the bloody roadside motel.
你要不要找人谈谈 艾登
Are you gonna talk to somebody about this, Aidan?
我能把持住
I got it under control.
我去冲个澡
I'm gonna hit the showers.
- 嘿 退伍军人事务部有消息吗 - 没有呢
- Hey, how'd it go with Veterans Affairs? - It didn't.
怎么 他们连伤残索赔数据库都没有吗
What, they don't have a database for disability claims?
哦 他们有
Oh, they do.
他们说要列个名单给我们
They said they could compile a list for us.
需要一份授权令和三周的通告
With a warrant and three weeks' notice.
接电话的那位女士说他们有两百多份现用档案
The woman we spoke to said there are over 200 active files.
而且还有上百人不在这个系统里
And hundreds of more people that aren't even in the system.
八十岁的退伍军人在外游荡不回家
80-year-old vets living in the streets.
我们把这些小伙子送去海外捱枪子儿
We send these guys overseas to get shot at,
他们回来的时候却缠着浸透鲜血的绷带
and they get tangled up in red tape when they come home.
好吧 肯定有办法找到这个家伙 四个退伍军人
OK, there's gotta be a way to find this guy. Four vets,
一起抢劫 其中一个有假肢
working together to stage a robbery. One with a prosthetic hand.
可能是创伤后应激障碍 别又批判我 我只是...
And possible PTSD. Don't start. I'm just...
- 这只是个人观点 - 不 你说的可能在理
- It's my opinion. - No, you might be on to something.
- 你去哪儿 - 调查
- Where are you going? - Recon.
我们曾经在北美最棒的
We were the best damn fighting unit
作战部队
in North America.
但他们对我们百般虐待
And they threw us out on our asses.
没有一句感谢
No thank yous,
也不给我们选择权
no options.
我呼吸了四个国家的尘垢啊 伙计
I sucked dirt in four countries, man.
却难防自己人的暗箭
To get stabbed in the back by my own.
我四处游荡 想...
I walk around looking to...
想找个人揍一顿
looking to punch somebody in the face.
期待着发生一件能让我解脱的事
Waiting for that one little thing that's gonna set me off, man.
好吧 这不是创伤后应激障碍
OK, that's not PTSD;
只说明你就是个混蛋
That's just you being an asshole.
让我们听一听我们的新成员的故事
Let's hear from the newest member
你何不介绍一下自己呢
of our group here. Why don't you introduce yourself?
我叫艾登 而且...
I'm Aidan. And...
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
你想谈谈吗
You feel like talking about it?
你的失眠
Your sleeplessness?
不太想
Not really.
这对他没用的
That's not gonna work for him.
你来是有原因的
You came for a reason.
我是个工作狂
I'm a workaholic.
我把工作带回家 我熬夜到很晚
I bring it home, I stay up too late.
你介意告诉我们你是干什么的吗
Do you mind if I ask what you do?
我是警察
I'm a cop.
我们中的第一个
That's a first for us.
你是警察 这是退伍军人小组 伙计
You're a cop? This is a veteran's group, man.
开枪杀人的时候穿着什么样的制服
It matter what uniform you're wearing
这个重要吗
when you shoot someone?
有道理
Fair enough.
你会重现当时的情景么 你提到的枪杀事件
Do you have flashbacks about it? The shooting you mentioned?
- 偶尔会 - 你会梦到吗
- Sometimes. - Do you dream about it?
- 不会 - 你会害怕
- No. - Are you afraid
- 你梦到它吗 - 我会控制
- of dreaming about it? - I deal with it.
- 我懂了- 我有失眠症 这是...
- I hear that. - I have insomnia. It's...
不 你没有 你有创伤后应激障碍
No you don't. You have Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder.
你拼命工作只是为了逃避睡眠
You're working your ass off to avoid sleeping.
别 别假装不是这样 至少别在这个组里
And don't... don't pretend otherwise. At least not with this group.
我自己 我在工作的时候晕倒在桌子上
Myself, I'd pass out at my desk at work.
我回来后在广告业干了一阵子
I was in advertising for a while when I got back.
我做完了自己的项目 就开始
If I finished my own project, I'd start work
帮别人做 什么都做 就是不让自己
on somebody else's. Anything to avoid
休息 不让我的思想停滞
relaxing, letting my mind open up.
因为一旦停下往事就会重现 对吗
'Cause that's when it hits you, right?
那么 是什么让一个警察来到退伍军人支援团的
So. What brings a cop to a veterans' support group?
看到了一则启事 觉得我可以试一试
Saw a notice. Thought I'd give it a try.
还有呢
And?
你想听真话
You want the truth?
呃...
Ah...
我觉得我的情况要好过他们大部分人
I think I'm doing better than most of those guys.
但你还是来了呀
And yet you're still here.
你想听真话吗
You want the truth?
我觉得他们有一半人今晚都会比你睡得香
I think half those guys will sleep better tonight than you will.
呃 我能问你个问题吗
Um, can I ask you a question?
- 作为一个警察吗 - 有一个人
- As a policeman? - There's a guy,
他有一只假手 可能是个退伍军人 病的不轻
he's got a prosthetic hand. He's probably a veteran, wound really tight.
小组是保密的
Group is confidential.
你不是医生 对吧
You're not a doctor, are ya?
不是
No.
你没得选 我可以拿到法院传令
It's not actually your choice. I could get a court order.
听着 我想逮捕那个家伙肯定不是因为他有假肢
Look, I'm not looking to arrest a guy just because he has a prosthetic hand.
我要找的这个人 他有武器
The guy I'm looking for, he's armed,
状况很糟 所以如果他碰巧是你的组员
he's in a really bad place. So if he happens to be one of your guys,
我不觉得你替他保守秘密是在帮他
I'm not sure how you keeping it a secret is gonna help him.
需要一个叫科瓦奇斯的人的现居住址
Need a current address on Kovacks.
K-o-v-a-c-k-s
K-O-V-A-C-K-S.
彼得・伊莱亚斯  两年前在阿富汗失去了一只手
Peter Elias. Lost his hand in Afghanistan two years ago.
我来找
I'm on it.
你从哪儿知道这个的
Where did you get this?
我参加了一个创伤后应激障碍小组
I joined a PTSD group.
- 退伍军人的创伤后应激障碍小组 - 嗯 他们没把我赶出来
- A veteran PTSD group? - Well, they didn't kick me out.
他们知道你为什么去吗
Did they know why you were there?
我为什么去很重要吗
Does it matter why I was there?
我能跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you one minute?
谢了 伙计 你把我从一堂说教里解救出来了
Thanks, man. You saved me from another lecture.
不 我没有
No, I didn't.
- 你参加了治疗小组 - 是的 而且我得到了引导
- You went into a therapy group? - Yeah, and I got a lead.
你知道这有多不合适吗
You understand how inappropriate that is?
这些人得互相信任
These people have to trust each other.
有什么大碍 他们不知道我去那里干嘛
Who's it hurt? They don't know why I'm there.
是的 但是他们有隐私权 而且有权知道是谁在听
Yeah, but they have a right to privacy. And to know who's listening,
特别是当他们在那里努力寻求治愈的时候
especially when they're there just to try and heal.
谢谢
Thank you.
找到了彼得・科瓦奇斯的服役记录
Alright, got a service record for Peter Kovacks.
二十年 职务从没超过下士
Twelve years, never rose above corporal.
去过一 二 三次阿富汗
One, two, three tours in Afghanistan.
六个月前退伍
Got out six months ago.
- 爆破专家 - 在一个防爆小组服役
- Explosives expert. - Served in a bomb disposal unit.
受过很多专业训练
Ton of specialist training too.
是那种哪怕自己也在屋子里 也会引爆炸弹炸开保险箱的家伙
Kind of guy who can shape a charge to blow open a safe while he's in the same room.
- 能找到他的地址吗 - 这上面没有写
- Can we get an address? - Not on here.
没有残疾 没有领抚恤金
No disability, not pulling a pension.
但是既然我们知道他在哪个部队服过役
But now that we know what unit he was in,
我们可以找找他的战友
we can find out who he served with.
我们还要找其他三个人
We're still looking for the other three.
- 嗨 我们应该把这个发给盗窃侦破组 - 是啊
- Hey, we should send this to Robbery. - Yeah,
- 这样能加快案子进展 - 不 她说得对
- 'cause that'll speed things up. - No. She's right.
他们有权知道
They need to know.
- 嗨 你要进来吗 - 嗯
- Hey, you comin'? - Yeah.
嗨
Hi.
- 你和彼特・科瓦奇斯一起服过役吗 - 有两个服役期
- So, you served with Pete Kovacks? - Two tours.
他的手被炸的时候你在场吗
Were you there when he lost his hand?
彼特有麻烦了吗
Is Pete in trouble?
我们必须找到他 你知道他在哪儿吗
We need to find him. Do you know where he is?
我们没有联系
We never kept in touch.
我俩退役的时候在佩塔瓦瓦见过他
Saw him at Petawawa when we were both getting out.
几个月前在体育酒吧遇见过
Ran into him at a sports bar a few months ago.
你能想到你们队里会有谁知道他的下落吗
Anyone else in your unit you can think of that might know where he is?
表示怀疑 彼特有些孤僻
I doubt it. Pete was a bit of a loner,
和队里的其他人处的不好
never really got along with the other guys in the unit.
- 他经常和123团的人在一起 - 他们在哪儿
- Spent a lot of time with the 123rd. - Where was that?
坎大哈
Kandahar.
我们在基地睡过临床 我们这些人都是这么认识的
We used to bunk beside each other on base. Guys got to know each other.
你认识杰西・鲍威尔吗
You know a guy named Jesse Powell?
认识 点头交而已
Sure. I mean, to say hello to, yeah.
彼特认识他吗
Did Pete know him?
他和杰西走得很近 互相照应
He and Jesse were close, looked out for each other.
我觉得彼特受伤的时候杰西应该在场
I think Jesse was there when Pete got injured.
如果想找彼特 你们应该去找杰西谈谈
If you wanna find Pete, you should talk to Jesse.
我们得走了 我们说好的
We gotta go, that was the deal!
干完这一票 我们就上路
We do the job, then we hit the road.
- 我做不到 - 你想被抓吗
- I can't. - You trying to get caught?
最近怎么样 兄弟
How you doing, buddy?
- 见到你真高兴 - 你有麻烦了
- Glad to see you. - You got trouble.
警察找我问铁杉珠宝店的事情了
The cops talked to me about Hemlock Jewels.
你得劝劝他 不然我们都要完蛋
You need to talk some sense into him, or we're all screwed.
他说得对 警察要抓你
He's right. They're gonna track you down.
你何不告诉我你接下来要怎么做
Why didn't you tell me what you were gonna do?
- 我不想连累你 - 我已经被连累了 警察以为我
- Didn't wanna get you involved. - Well, I am! They think
- 帮忙策划了 - 告诉他们你没做过就好了
- that I helped plan it. - Just tell 'em you didn't do it.
他们说你大喊大叫 还在大街上开枪
They said you were screaming. That you shot up the street.
- 发生什么了 - 我不知道 好吗
- What happened? - I don't know, OK?
我朝货车走过去
I'm walking to the van,
接下来 我感觉我又回到了战场 伙计
and next thing I know, I'm right back there, man.
就在战斗最激烈的时刻
Right in the thick of it.
那些景象 声音
Sights, sounds,
所有一切 我当时魂都吓没了
everything, man. It scared the shit out of me.
你得控制住自己
You gotta get a hold of yourself.
警察会找上门来的
The cops, they're gonna find you here.
- 你当我不知道吗 - 那你他妈就赶紧离开镇上啊
- You don't think I know that? - So get the hell out of town!
我做不到 我不能那么做
I can't! I can't do that!
听我说 我离开这里就再没安全可言了 我真的做不到
Look, it's not safe for me out there anymore. Man, it's... I can't.
那就跟我一起 我们一起走
So come with me. We'll go together.
不 你根本没听懂
No! You're not listening!
如果我出去了
If I go out there,
我就会陷入不利 而且无路可逃
I'm pinned down and there's no way out.
那你准备怎么做
So what are you gonna do?
只要他们别管我 我就不会有事的
If they leave me alone, I'll be fine.
- 但那是不可能的... - 只能这样
- But that's not gonna happen... - That's the way it is!
- 我们等够了 - 我们撤了
- We're done waiting. - We're out of here.
别管他们了 好吗
Just forget 'em! OK?
我就在这儿呆着了
I'm making a stand here.
如果事情就这样结束了 那就顺其自然吧
And if this is the way it ends, then so be it.
但我是不会走的
But I'm not moving.
不会因为你 或者其他人而改变主意
Not for you or anybody else.
我们浏览了彼特和杰西所有的个人资料
We've gone through all of Pete and Jesse's personnel files.
大部分很详尽 但还是有一些遗漏
Most are accounted for, but there's still a few hold-outs.
有人找到劫匪的消息了吗
Does anyone look good for the robbery?
罗杰・兰代尔 海军陆战队中士
Roger Langdale. Sergeant.
彼特的最后一个服役期时在坎大哈服役
Served in Kandahar for Pete's last tour.
他的室友说他今天早上往车上装行李 说要去长途旅行
His roommate said he packed up his car this morning, going on a long trip.
我们会发布他的车牌号和外貌描述的通缉令
We got a dispatch to send out a plate number and a description.
- 那杰西・鲍威尔呢 - 一无所获
- What about Jesse Powell? - No dice.
我们去避难所调查过了 他收拾东西离开了
We checked the shelter; he's packed up and moved on.
他们都人间蒸发了似的
They're all scattering in the wind.
- 杰西不会的 - 为什么
- Not Jesse. Not yet. - Why not?
他还有一件事情要做
He's still got something he's gotta do.
- 你儿子的生日你都迟到 - 迟到比不来好多了
- Late for your son's birthday. - Better late than never.
进来 这边
Get in. Come on.
嗨 杰西
Hey, Jesse.
呃 别走
Uh, uh, uh, uh. No, no.
你的四个老战友抢了你之前送货的珠宝店
So four guys rob a store on your old route.
他们四个知道店里有什么 因为有人对他们泄密了
Four guys who know what's inside 'cause someone tipped them off.
他们其中一个人有一只假手
And one of them has a prosthetic hand.
- 你知道有人符合这些条件吗 - 我不知道是谁
- Anyone you know match that description? - No one I can think of.
那个叫彼特・科瓦奇斯的家伙呢
How about a guy named Pete Kovacks?
我希望你能明白一些事情 杰西
I want you to understand something here, Jesse.
你就要越界了
You're about to cross a line.
你之前就不配合我们 直到现在你还在说谎
You were uncooperative before. As of right now, you keep lying,
我们可以指控你妨碍司法公正
you're going to be facing charges. Obstruction of justice.
教唆犯罪和共谋
Aiding and abetting. And conspiracy.
彼特和我一起在坎大哈服役
Pete and I were in Kandahar.
还有很多人一起
Lots of guys were.
回来之后你见过他吗
Have you seen him since you came back?
- 偶尔 - 你跟他说过铁杉珠宝店的事吗
- Time to time. - You tell him about Hemlock Jewels?
没有 我不知道 也许说过
No. I don't know. Maybe.
我不记得了 我喝醉了
I don't remember, OK. I was drunk.
你说过只要你醒着就都记得
You said you always remember, as long as you're awake.
好吧 就算说了又怎样
OK, so what if I did?
谈论自己的工作不算犯罪吧
It's not a crime to talk about your work.
要是谋划抢劫的话就是了
It is if you're planning a robbery.
我跟那件事一点关系都没有
I didn't have anything to do with it.
我也不会帮助你们抓我的朋友
And I'm not going to help you put one of my friends away.
如果你觉得他犯了罪 那你就自己去抓他
You think he did something, catch him yourself.
你真的觉得你这是在帮彼特吗 杰西
You really think you're helping Pete, Jesse?
彼特只是碰巧闯入了
Pete just broke
一个与从前相似的场景 他进门 出门 收工了
into a place like a pro. He was in, out, done.
然后有些事触发了他的记忆
But then something set him off.
他袭击了一个女人 还开了枪
He attacked a woman and he fired his weapon.
你要是丢下彼特不管 任他在这条路上走下去
You leave Pete out there, on the path that he's on,
他迟早会闹出人命的
he's gonna kill someone.
刚刚接到了伊利堡边境处的电话
Just got a call from the border crossing at Fort Erie.
他们截住了一辆车 跟兰代尔的牌照相符 车上有三个男人
They stopped a car matching Langdale's plates. Three men,
后备箱还有二十万美金现钞
200 grand in cash in the trunk.
我们要找的珠宝店劫匪
Our jewelry thieves.
我们会查清楚的 他们已经扣留了这三个人准备审讯
We'll find out. They're holding them for questioning.
去吧
Go.
你知道吗 我觉得彼特已经不止患有创伤后应激障碍那么简单了
You know, I think Pete's got more than just PTSD.
我觉得他另有所图
I think he's got an axe to grind.
而且我认为你知道这是为什么
And I think you know why.
他脑子里到底在想什么 杰西
What's going on inside his head, Jesse?
我不知道
I don't know that.
他失去手的时候你在现场吗
Were you there when he lost his hand?
跟我们说说吧 杰西
Tell us about it, Jesse.
彼特是个好人
Pete was a good guy.
他就像冰一样
He was like ice.
任何人都不能影响他
You couldn't rattle him.
他就是为防爆任务而生的
Guy was built for bomb squad duty.
当时我们正要撤离一个城镇
We were clearing out a town.
塔利班之前去过 还炸毁了一所学校
Taliban had come in and blown up a school.
作为对同意女孩入学的惩罚
Punishment for letting girls attend.
到处都是狙击手和爆炸装置
Left a bunch of sniper nests, IEDs everywhere.
警报响个不停
Sirens going off the whole time.
我们走过一栋又一栋房子
We're moving house to house,
很慢 很有秩序 让防爆组的人
slow and methodical, letting the bomb guys
清理每个房间 我们接到一条信息
clear out each room. We get a message
让我们朝这条街道进发
to start working down this one street,
意思就是他们已经消灭了所有的狙击手
meaning they've cleared the snipers out.
后来事实证明我们错了
Turns out that's not right.
我旁边的那个家伙喉部中枪 我和彼特
Guy next to me takes one in the throat. Me and Pete
请求支援 但我们知道已经来不及了
are calling out for support, but we both know it's not gonna make it in time.
所以我们逃跑了
So we ran.
可能没看到警报网线
Missed a trip-wire, I guess.
那是触发装置
That's what they were using for triggers, these little bits
用几乎看不见的鱼线做的 彼特绊动了它
of fishing line you can barely see. Pete took it full on,
但他穿着防弹服
but he had his suit on,
所以只失去了手
so all he lost was his hand.
- 他失去的不仅仅是手 对吧 - 是的
- And that's not all he lost, huh? - No.
你去排查某个荒凉的地方
You go over to some godforsaken place,
那里的人根本不想你去
they don't even want ya.
因为他们分不清你是好人还是坏人
Can't tell the good guys from the bad guys,
任何人都有可能在你背后开枪 这一切都为了什么呢
everybody maybe gonna put a bullet in your back. For what?
为了回家
So you can come home
然后发现根本没人在意你吗
and realise no one gives a shit?
没人知道我们为什么而战
No one has a damn clue what we're fighting for.
人们都觉得你疯了
People looking at you like you're crazy,
觉得你神智有问题
like there's something wrong with you.
因为确实是
'Cause there is.
杰西 彼特需要你
Pete needs you, Jesse.
你知道的
You know that.
为什么不告诉我们他在哪儿呢
So why don't you just tell us where he is?
我带你们去找他
I'll take you to him.
为什么不直接告诉我们地址呢
Why don't you just give us the address?
除非让我和你们一起去
Only if you let me come with you.
- 你在做什么 - 什么意思 你也听到他说的
- What are you doing? - What do you mean? You heard the guy.
他和我们一起去才会说出地点
He's not gonna give us the location unless he comes with.
一个我行我素的人还不够吗 还得弄得更复杂吗
One loose cannon isn't enough? We need to complicate the situation?
- 你想我们怎么做 - 彼特・科瓦奇斯极其危险
- What would you have us do? - Pete Kovacks is extremely dangerous.
如果他感到了威胁 可能会变得很暴力
If he feels threatened, he could turn violent.
我们知道
We've got it.
小心点
Just be careful.
蹲下 蹲下
Stay down. Stay down.
弗伦 到底怎么回事
Phalen? What the hell is going on? The instructions
上级指示设立安全范围 隐藏起来
were to establish a perimeter and stay out of sight.
一个巡警靠近了大楼 操之过急
So patrolman approached the building. He jumped the gun.
大楼里的人就开枪了
Guy inside opened fire.
他差点死在那儿了
Patrolman barely got out of there alive.
- 放烟雾弹把他熏出来 - 没用 他有防雾面具
- We're gonna have to gas him out. - Won't work. Mask.
- 抱歉 你是谁 - 疑犯的朋友
- I'm sorry, who are you? - He's a friend of the suspect.
他们在阿富汗一起服过役
They served together in Afghanistan.
杰西 你能和他谈谈吗
Jesse, you think you can talk to him?
我可以试试
I can try.
布莱克 等等 他是个平民
Hold on there, Black. This guy's a civilian.
我见过的战火比你多了去了
Bet I've seen more hostile fire than you.
我们让他试试
We're gonna give him a shot.
谁给我个扩音器
Someone get me a megaphone.
杰西 和他谈谈
Talk to him, Jesse.
彼特 我是杰西
Pete, it's Jesse.
伙计们 他被困在里面 这声音只会让他感觉更糟
Guys, he's boxed in. The noise is probably just gonna make it worse.
我必须和他谈谈
I gotta talk to him.
哇哦 杰西 等等 伙计
Whoa, whoa, Jesse, hold on, man!
艾登 艾登
Aidan! Aidan!
彼特
Pete?
彼特 外面有个战略小队
Pete, there's a tactical squad outside
他们只用三十秒就能攻破这里
that's gonna bust in here in about 30 seconds.
他们进来时 我可不想在这里
I'd rather not be here when that happens,
但你不走 我是不会出去的
but I'm not leaving without you.
就像在那里的战火风暴一样 伙计
Just like that shit storm over there, buddy.
我们得一起出去
We got to get out of this together.
彼特
Pete?
我是艾登・布莱克警探
This is Detective Aidan Black.
放下你的武器
I need you to surrender your weapon.
趴下
Down!
彼特 要是非得开枪的话 那就从我开始
Pete, if there's gonna be any shooting, it's gonna start with me.
杰西 别逼我
Don't make me do this, Jesse.
都不要开枪 没必要出现伤亡
There's not gonna be any shooting, alright? Nobody needs to get hurt here.
你们两个现在都出去
Get out! Both of you, now!
彼特 我办不到 我们现在是在同一条船上
I can't do that, Pete. We're all in this together now.
放下枪
Drop the gun.
不 我得保护自己
No! I need to protect myself.
朋友 我知道你很害怕 相信我 我明白那种感受
Look, man, I understand you're afraid. Believe me, I know what that feels like.
但你这样不是在保护自己
But you're not protecting yourself.
只会让自己中枪身亡 彼特 你知道的
You're just gonna get yourself shot, Pete, and you know it.
没人会在乎 对吧
And what's that gonna matter to anyone else, huh?
那我呢
How about me?
在亲眼见证了战争的残酷之后
You gonna make me watch that happen? Huh, Pete?
你还想让我目睹这一切吗 彼特
After what we've seen?
你还要再给我一个无法合眼的理由吗
You gonna give me another reason I can't close my eyes?
杰西 你不该来这儿的
You shouldn't be here, Jesse.
不 我就该来
Yes, I damn well should!
我做过什么好事吗 唯一的好事就是
The hell else am I good for? One of the only good things I ever did
把你从那鬼地方救出来 为了什么
was carry you out of that shithole place. For what?
就是为了让你把自己和一群警察
So you can blow yourself all to hell
一起炸死吗
and take a bunch of cops with you?
彼特 什么时候才是个头儿啊
Where's it all end, Pete?
你杀了我 接着呢
You kill me, then what?
杀了杰西 让卢卡斯在没有父亲的陪伴下成长
Kill Jesse here and let Lucas grow up without a father?
杀了外面的警察 让他们的孩子成为遗孤
Kill a bunch of cops out there, let their kids suffer?
朋友 只有两种结局
There's only two ways this is going down, man.
要不我们三人一起出去 要不都别出去
Either all three of us walk out of here together, or we don't.
就像其他人一样
And our names get forgotten
我们的名字将被遗忘
just like everyone else's.
你来选择
It's your choice.
再次成为真正的英雄 感觉怎么样
How's it feel to be a bona fide hero again?
走吧 如果快点
Come on, man, if we hurry,
还能赶回去吃你儿子的生日蛋糕
we can make it back for your son's birthday in time for cake.
走吧
Let's go.
你好 我是丹妮拉・雷德利
Hi, this is Daniella Ridley. I'd like to speak to someone
我想和一个跟领养儿童保持联系的人讲话
about getting in touch with a child who was put up for adoption.
有时把枪掏出后 事情迅速变得很疯狂
Sometimes the guns come out and it all gets cranked up to insanity
以至于怀疑自己还能不能回到家
and you're down to wondering if you're ever gonna make it home,
但几分钟后
and then a couple minutes later
你走出来 像什么事都没发生一样
you're walking out like nothing happened.
我更喜欢没人受伤
I like it better when no one gets hurt.
我打赌战略小队的人今晚会称你为高手
Tactical guys are calling you some kind of hotshot tonight, I bet.
因为他们嫉妒
Only 'cause they're jealous.
再喝一轮
Mmhmm. Another round?
我得去个地方
I actually gotta be somewhere.
你请我出来然后急着就走了
You invited me out to rush me off?
- 是你请我出来的 - 管它是谁请谁
- You invited me. - He said, she said.
我在做的事
This thing I'm doing...
希望能帮助我
I hope it's gonna help me.
帮助我们
Us.
我们
Us?
你懂我的意思
You know what I mean.
我喜欢你那么说
I like the sound of that.
很好
Good.
那好 我就...
Alright, I'll...
再见
I'll see you later.
卢卡斯 我的孩子
So my kid, Lucas,
他想造个火箭
he wants to build a rocket.
我说他疯了 他说没有
I say he's crazy, he says no.
他有一个DIY工具箱 所以...
He's got this little do-it-yourself kit. So...
我在装推进器时
I'm loading the propellant in
突然 我的手开始发抖
and all of a sudden, my hands just start shaking.
我知道那是安全的
I mean, it's safe, right?
但 你们懂
But... you know.
你最后装完了吗
Did you finish building it?
我休息了会儿
I took a little break,
然后回去把那玩意弄好了
went back and packed that bastard to the gills
接着把它炸掉
and we blew her off.
他笑个不停
He couldn't get the smile off his face.
所以 你懂的
So, you know,
相当美好的一天
it was a pretty good day.
你想讲讲你的故事吗
You want to go?
我叫艾登
Uh, my name is Aidan.
嗯...
And, uh...
我需要帮助
I need help.
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 shinybbs.com
深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub